Guide to the Robert Louis Laing McCormick Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- TRADE RELATIONS COUNCIL FILES, Series II
  - Trade Relations Council
    - Topical files
      - Simson, Congressman Richard M., 1959, 1960, undated (Box 64, Folder 1041-1044)
      - Southern Governors Conference, 1959 (Box 64, Folder 1045)
      - Stewart, Eugene, 1962, undated (Box 64, Folder 1046)
      - Strackbein, O. R., 1959-1962, undated (Box 64, Folder 1047-1048)
      - Tritsch, John G., 1961-1963 (Box 64, Folder 1049)
      - T.V.A. turbogenerator, 1959, undated (Box 64, Folder 1050)
      - U.S. Chamber of Commerce Annual meeting, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 1051-1054)
      - Woolen hearings: Tariff Commission, 1959 (Box 64, Folder 1055)
      - Zoll, Fred, Jr., 1962, 1963 (Box 64, Folder 1056)
    - Inter-Industry Committee
      - General, 1962, undated (Box 65, Folder 1057-1059)
      - Boarman, Patrick M., 1962, undated (Box 65, Folder 1060-1063)
      - Gloversville, N.Y. Chamber of Commerce, 1962, undated (Box 65, Folder 1064)
      - Hearings on H.R. 9900, 1961, 1962, undated (Box 65, Folder 1065-1068)
      - Memorandum of conference, 1962 (Box 65, Folder 1069)
    - Legislation
      - Analyses of H.R. 9900, 1961, 1962, undated (Box 66, Folder 1070)
      - Analyses of Trade bill, 1962, undated (Box 66, Folder 1071)
      - Congressional bills, 1961, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 1072-1073)
      - Congressional reprints during Trade bill hearings, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 1074-1076)
      - Customs simplification, 1960 (Box 66, Folder 1077)
      - G.A.T.T. Tariff conference: Geneva, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 1078)
      - House and Senate reports on H.R. 11790, 1962, undated (Box 66, Folder 1079)
      - Investigations under the "Escape clause", 1961 (Box 66, Folder 1080)
      - President's Trade message, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 1081)
      - Staff memorandum: "Proprieties of Pressures Exerted in Support of H.R. 9900", undated (Box 66, Folder 1082)
      - Tariff act of 1930 (Box 66, Folder 1083)
      - Testimony by Robert L. L. McCormick before the Senate Finance Committee on H.R. 11790, 1962, undated (Box 66, Folder 1084-1085)
      - Trade Agreements Extension act, 1957, 1958 (Box 66, Folder 1086-1088)
      - Trade Expansion act of 1962 (Box 66, Folder 1089-1091)
      - "Zero List": presented by Secretary of Commerce during hearing on Trade bill, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 1092)
- TRADE FILES, Series III
  - General Correspondence, 1956
    - A (Box 67, Folder 1093)
    - Arnaboldi, Leo P., Jr., 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1094)
    - B, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1095)
    - Burns, Louis J., Jr., 1954-1956, undated (Box 67, Folder 1096-1097)
    - C, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1098)
    - Calhoun, Leonard, 1955, 1956, undated (Box 67, Folder 1099)
    - Coates, Charles B., 1955 (Box 67, Folder 1100)
    - D, 1956, undated (Box 67, Folder 1101)
    - E, 1955, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1102)
    - F, 1955 (Box 67, Folder 1103)
    - G, 1955 (Box 67, Folder 1104)
    - H, 1955, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1105)
    - Hennessey, John, 1956, undated (Box 67, Folder 1106)
    - Hodgdon, Dorothy, undated (Box 67, Folder 1107-1108)
    - I, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1109)
    - J, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1110)
    - K, 1955, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1111)
    - L, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1112)
    - Linville, Donald, 1956, undated (Box 67, Folder 1113)
    - (M) Alpha, 1955, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1114)
    - McCormick, Robert L. L., 1954-1956, undated (Box 67, Folder 1115)
    - McLendon, Major L. P., 1955, 1956, undated (Box 67, Folder 1116)
    - Mitchell, Reginald, 1954, 1955 (Box 67, Folder 1117)
    - N, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1118)
    - P, 1955, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1119)
    - R, 1955, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 1120)
    - Rosenbloom, M. V., 1954, 1955, undated (Box 67, Folder 1121)
    - S (Box 68, Folder 1122)
    - Staples, William D., 1954-1956, undated (Box 68, Folder 1123-1127)
    - T, 1955, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 1128)
    - W, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 1129)
    - Weck, Egon E., 1956 (Box 68, Folder 1130)
    - Z, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 1131)
  - Administrative memoranda, undated (Box 68, Folder 1132-1135)
  - Clippings, 1954-1959 (Box 68, Folder 1136-1142)
  - Clippings (cont'd), 1959 (Box 69, Folder 1143-1156)
  - Clippings (cont'd), 1960 (Box 70, Folder 1157-1170)
  - Clippings (cont'd), 1960-1962 (Box 71, Folder 1171-1183)
  - Clippings (cont'd), 1962, 1963, undated (Box 72, Folder 1184-1194)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 72, Folder 1195-1196)
  - Confidential memoranda (1-95), undated (Box 73, Folder 1197-1199)
  - Research bulletins (vols. 1 and 2), undated (Box 73, Folder 1200-1212)
  - Topical files
    - Advertisements, 1955, undated (Box 74, Folder 1213-1214)
    - Associations (National), 1955 (Box 74, Folder 1215)
    - American Tariff League
      - Annual meeting, 1955 (Box 74, Folder 1216)
      - Correspondence, 1954-1956, undated (Box 74, Folder 1217-1219)
      - League Letters, 1954-1956 (Box 74, Folder 1220)
      - Packet, 1955, undated (Box 74, Folder 1221)
      - Publications, 1944-1955, undated (Box 74, Folder 1222-1223)
      - Releases, 1955, 1956 (Box 74, Folder 1224)
      - Topics, 1955 (Box 74, Folder 1225)
    - Balance of payments, undated (Box 74, Folder 1226)
    - Bibliographies, undated (Box 74, Folder 1227)
    - Business Advisory Council, 1954, 1955, undated (Box 74, Folder 1228)
    - Chamber of Commerce of the U.S.
      - General, 1885-1955 (Box 74, Folder 1229-1230)
      - General, 1956, undated (Box 75, Folder 1231)
      - Referendum 95, 1955, 1956, undated (Box 75, Folder 1232-1234)
    - Charts, maps, etc., 1956, undated (Box 75, Folder 1235-1237)
    - Checklist for H.R. 1, 1955 (Box 75, Folder 1238)
    - Comic book, 1955, undated (Box 75, Folder 1239-1240)
    - Committee for a National Trade Policy, 1951-1955 (Box 75, Folder 1241-1245)
    - Committee for a National Trade Policy, 1955, 1956, undated (Box 76, Folder 1246-1249)
    - Committee for Reciprocity Information, 1955 (Box 76, Folder 1250)
    - Congressmen, 1955 (Box 76, Folder 1251)
    - Coulter, Dr. John Lee, 1955 (Box 76, Folder 1252)
    - "Dollar Gap", 1955 (Box 76, Folder 1253)
    - Fact sheets, 1955 undated (Box 76, Folder 1254-1255)
    - Fellers, General, 1956 (Box 76, Folder 1256)
    - Foreign protests re "Escape clause", 1955, undated (Box 76, Folder 1257)
    - Industry Analysis: Senate Finance Committee, undated (Box 76, Folder 1258-1259)
    - Letters (suggested), undated (Box 76, Folder 1260)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1955 (Box 76, Folder 1261)
    - Lloyd's book: Tariffs: The Case for Protection, 1955, undated (Box 76, Folder 1262-1264)
    - Lubell, Samuel: The Revolution in World Trade, 1955, undated (Box 76, Folder 1265-1267)
    - Mailing lists, 1955, 1956, undated (Box 77, Folder 1268)
    - Manual for State Organizations, 1954, 1955, undated (Box 77, Folder 1269)
    - Memos requested by Congressmen, 1953-1956, undated (Box 77, Folder 1270)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1956, undated (Box 77, Folder 1271-1274)
    - Mollahan speech: Gallup Poll, 1955 (Box 77, Folder 1275)
    - Montage, 1955 (Box 77, Folder 1276)
    - National Foreign Trade Council, Inc., 1955, 1956 (Box 77, Folder 1277)
    - New Members Program, 1955, undated (Box 77, Folder 1278-1279)
    - Perspective (American Tariff League), 1955 (Box 77, Folder 1280)
    - Petition signatories (press release by A. T. L.), 1956, undated (Box 77, Folder 1281)
    - Plants: locations, undated (Box 77, Folder 1282)
    - President's letter re "Bicycle Industry", 1955, undated (Box 77, Folder 1283)
    - Randall, Clarence, 1948-1956, undated (Box 77, Folder 1284)
    - Report on Activities (Trade Information Committee), 1955, undated (Box 77, Folder 1285)
    - Resolutions, 1955 (Box 77, Folder 1286)
    - Speeches (suggested) for Congressmen, 1956, undated (Box 77, Folder 1287-1288)
  - Legislation
    - "The Agreement on the Organization for Trade Cooperation", 1956 (Box 78, Folder 1289)
    - Articles of the O. T. C., undated (Box 78, Folder 1290)
    - Commerce Department: Secretary Week's Memo, 1956, undated (Box 78, Folder 1291)
    - Conference reports, 1955 (Box 78, Folder 1292)
    - Congressional reports, 1954-1956 (Box 78, Folder 1293-1294)
    - Customs Simplification Act, 1955, 1956, undated (Box 78, Folder 1295-1299)
    - Customs survey showing effects of proposed changes in Tariff Act, 1955 (Box 78, Folder 1300)
    - General Agreements on Tariffs and Trade (Box 78, Folder 1301)
      - Hearings, 1955 (Box 78, Folder 1301)
      - "International Trade News Bulletin", undated (Box 78, Folder 1302)
      - Malone speech, 1955, 1956 (Box 78, Folder 1303)
      - 0.T.C., 1950-1955, undated (Box 78, Folder 1304-1305)
      - Staples, W. D., 1955 (Box 78, Folder 1306)
    - House Resolution 1, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 1307-1310)
    - House Resolution 459, 1956 (Box 79, Folder 1311)
    - House Resolution 5550, 1956, undated (Box 79, Folder 1312-1317)
    - House Resolution 5559, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 1318)
    - House Resolution 6040, 1955, 1956, undated (Box 79, Folder 1319-1321)
    - House Resolution 6059, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 1322)
    - House Resolutions: miscellaneous, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 1323)
    - Lufthansa and G. A. T. T., 1955 (Box 79, Folder 1324)
    - McLendon, Lennox P.: "The Legal Sweep of H.R. 5550", 1956 (Box 79, Folder 1325)
    - Organization for Trade Cooperation
      - General, 1955, undated (Box 79, Folder 1326-1327)
      - House Resolution 5550, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 1328)
      - White House correspondence on H.R. 5550, 1955, undated (Box 79, Folder 1329)
    - Public Laws, 1954-1956 (Box 79, Folder 1330)
    - Senate
      - Bridges, Styles, 1955 (Box 80, Folder 1331-1333)
      - Conference version of H.R. 1, 1955 (Box 80, Folder 1334)
      - Letter campaign, 1955 (Box 80, Folder 1335)
    - Southern States Industrial Council, 1956 (Box 80, Folder 1336)
    - Special Area: Agriculture, undated (Box 80, Folder 1337)
    - Special Area: Farm; "A Conflict of Programs", 1956 (Box 80, Folder 1338)
    - Statements: miscellaneous, 1953-1956 (Box 80, Folder 1339)
    - Steering Committee, 1955, undated (Box 80, Folder 1340)
    - Stockholders letters, 1955, undated (Box 80, Folder 1341)
    - Strackbein Committee, 1953-1956, undated (Box 80, Folder 1342-1344)
    - Sugar Act of 1948, 1947 (Box 80, Folder 1345)
    - Swiss, 1954, 1955, undated (Box 80, Folder 1346)
    - Telegrams re H.R. 1, 1955 (Box 80, Folder 1347)
    - Utt speech, undated (Box 80, Folder 1348)
    - Senate
      - Voting record on. H.R. 1, 1955, 1956 (Box 80, Folder 1349)
      - White House releases, 1955, 1956, undated (Box 80, Folder 1350)
      - White Paper No. 1, 1954, 1955 (Box 80, Folder 1351)
  - Companies
    - General, 1955, 1956, undated (Box 81, Folder 1352)
    - Allied Chemical and Dye Corporation, 1956 (Box 81, Folder 1353)
    - American Zinc, Lead and Smelting Company, 1954-1956, undated (Box 81, Folder 1354-1355)
    - Cincinnati Milling Machine Company., 1954-1956 (Box 81, Folder 1356)
    - The Dow Chemical Company, 1954-1956, undated (Box 81, Folder 1357-1361)
    - E. I. du Pont de Nemours and Company, 1955, 1956 (Box 81, Folder 1362)
    - Forstmann Woolen Company, 1954-1956 (Box 81, Folder 1363-1364)
    - General Plywood Corporation, 1955, 1956 (Box 81, Folder 1365-1366)
    - B. F. Goodrich Company, 1954-1956 (Box 81, Folder 1367)
    - Ketchum, MacLeod and Grove Inc., 1954-1956, undated (Box 81, Folder 1368-1370)
    - Koppers Company, Inc., 1955, 1956 (Box 82, Folder 1371-1372)
    - Libbey-Owens-Ford Glass Company, 1954-1956 (Box 82, Folder 1373)
    - Maloney Electric Company, 1955, 1956 (Box 82, Folder 1374)
    - Masonite Corporation, 1954-1956 (Box 82, Folder 1375)
    - Monsanto Chemical Company, 1953-1956, undated (Box 82, Folder 1376-1382)
    - Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company, 1954-1956, undated (Box 82, Folder 1383-1385)
    - Plymouth Oil Company, 1956 (Box 82, Folder 1386)
    - Rockwell Manufacturing Company, 1954-1956 (Box 83, Folder 1387-1388)
    - Victor Chemical Works/Victor International, 1956 (Box 83, Folder 1389)
    - Westinghouse Electrical Corporation, 1954-1956, undated (Box 83, Folder 1390-1394)
  - Congress
    - Analysis of Arkansas districts, 1955 (Box 83, Folder 1395)
    - Analysis of districts: House Ways and Means Committee, 1955 (Box 83, Folder 1396)
    - Senate Debate
      - General, 1955 (Box 83, Folder 1397)
      - Senator Beall, 1955, undated (Box 83, Folder 1398)
      - Senator Bridges, 1955 (Box 83, Folder 1399)
      - Senator Pastore, 1955 (Box 83, Folder 1400)
  - Index cards, undated (Box 84)
  - Index cards, undated (Box 85)
  - Index cards, undated (Box 86)
  - Index cards, undated (Box 87)
- PUBLICATIONS, Series IV
  - Trade Relations Council
    - A New Era of World Trade…, undated (Box 88, Folder 1401)
    - Application for Membership, 1959, undated (Box 88, Folder 1402)
    - A Proposed Trade Policy in the National Interest, undated (Box 88, Folder 1403)
    - Back Door to Trouble, 1955, undated (Box 88, Folder 1404)
    - Booklet, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 1405)
    - Bumper stickers, undated (Box 88, Folder 1406)
    - Fact Book, 1962, undated (Box 88, Folder 1407)
    - G.A.T.T. Spells T.R.O.U.B.L.E., 1956, undated (Box 88, Folder 1408)
    - Guide series, 1955, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 1409)
    - Ideas-Answers-Actions in Competitive World Trade, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 1410)
    - Pamphlets, books, miscellaneous, undated (Box 88, Folder 1411)
    - Pattern of G.A.T.T., undated (Box 88, Folder 1412)
    - Posters, undated (Box 88, Folder 1413-1414)
    - President's Letter, 1960, 1961 (Box 88, Folder 1415)
    - Press releases, 1959-1962, undated (Box 88, Folder 1416)
    - Projects Check-List and Cost, 1956 (Box 88, Folder 1417)
    - Strength at Home, undated (Box 88, Folder 1418)
    - TARIFFS are a job's best friend, 1956, undated (Box 88, Folder 1419)
    - Trade and tariff Packet, 1956 (Box 88, Folder 1420)
    - Tradelines, 1961, 1962 (Box 88, Folder 1421)
    - Tradeways, 1959-1961, undated (Box 88, Folder 1422)
    - T.R.C. Bulletin, 1959-1962 (Box 89, Folder 1423-1424)
    - T.R.C. Guide, 1959-1962, undated (Box 89, Folder 1425)
    - The Trojan Horse, undated (Box 89, Folder 1426)
    - Trouble with G.A.T.T.-0.T.C. and H.R. 5550, 1955, 1956, undated (Box 89, Folder 1427-1428)
    - The United States in World Trade, 1958 (Box 89, Folder 1429)
    - Willoughby and the Loreiei, 1956, undated (Box 89, Folder 1430-1431)
    - Willoughby and the Wooden Horse, undated (Box 89, Folder 1432-1433)
    - Willoughby's way Abroad, undated (Box 89, Folder 1434)
  - Publications of Others
    - Administration and Operation of Customs and Tariff Laws…, 1956 (Box 90, Folder 1435-1437)
    - American Tariff League: Hollywood at the Crossroads, 1957, 1958 (Box 90, Folder 1438)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1959-1962 (Box 90, Folder 1439-1440)
    - Commerce Department, 1959-1961 (Box 90, Folder 1441-1444)
    - Committee for a National Trade Policy, 1959-1962, undated (Box 91, Folder 1445-1446)
    - European Community, 1958, 1961 (Box 91, Folder 1447)
    - G.A.T.T.: Analysis of United States Negotiation, 1956 (Box 91, Folder 1448)
    - Impact of Imports and Exports on Employment, 1961 (Box 91, Folder 1449)
    - Joint Council on Economic Education, 1959-1962 (Box 91, Folder 1450)
    - Labor Department, 1959-1961 (Box 91, Folder 1451-1452)
    - Miscellaneous, 1958-1960 (Box 91, Folder 1453-1455)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960-1962, undated (Box 92, Folder 1456-1459)
    - State Department, 1955-1963 (Box 92, Folder 1460-1462)
    - Tariff Commission, 1959-1962 (Box 92, Folder 1463-1465)
    - Tariff Commission, 1962, 1963 (Box 93, Folder 1466-1468)
    - Treasury Department, 1959, 1960 (Box 93, Folder 1469)
    - Unemployment Benefit Advisors, Inc.: The Advisor, 1962 (Box 93, Folder 1470)
    - U.S. Press Association, 1961-1963 (Box 93, Folder 1471-1472)
    - U.S. Tariff Commission: The Tariff and its History, 1934 (Box 93, Folder 1473)
    - White House, 1959, 1960 (Box 93, Folder 1474)
  - Companies
    - American Textile Manufacturers Institute, Inc., 1959-1963, undated (Box 94, Folder 1475-1477)
    - Burlington Mills Corporation, 1954, 1955 (Box 94, Folder 1478)
    - S.H. Kress and Company, 1959 (Box 94, Folder 1479)
    - Libbey-Owens-Ford Glass Company, 1959 (Box 94, Folder 1480)
    - McCoy, Horace, 1960, 1961, undated (Box 94, Folder 1481-1482)
    - Monsanto Chemical Company, 1959, 1960 (Box 94, Folder 1483)
    - Morgantown Glassware Guild, 1955 (Box 94, Folder 1484-1490)
    - New York, 1959-1961 (Box 94, Folder 1491-1492)
    - Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company, 1962 (Box 94, Folder 1493)
    - J.P. Stevens and Company, Inc., 1959-1962 (Box 94, Folder 1494)
    - Westinghouse Electrical Corporation, 1959, 1960, undated (Box 94, Folder 1495)
- 1983 JUNE ADDITION, Series V
  - Citizens Commission on the Hoover Report
    - Memoranda, 1949 (Box 95, Folder 1496)
    - Press release, 1950 (Box 95, Folder 1497)
    - Printed material, 1953-1955 (Box 95, Folder 1498-1499)
  - Correspondence, 1964, 1965 (Box 95, Folder 1500-1506)
  - Presidential campaign 1968
    - The Answer Book, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 1507-1508)
    - Report, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 1509)
  - U.S. Military Government in Germany
    - "F.E.A. Disarmament Plan for Germany", 1945 (Box 97, Folder 1510-1511)
    - History, 1945 (Box 97, Folder 1512)
    - Information, 1946, undated (Box 97, Folder 1513-1514)
    - Memoranda, 1945 (Box 97, Folder 1515-1516)
    - Memoranda, 1945, 1946 (Box 98, Folder 1517)
    - Organization manual, 1946 (Box 98, Folder 1518)
    - Plan of Organization, undated (Box 98, Folder 1519)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 98, Folder 1520)
    - Projects, 1946 (Box 98, Folder 1521)
    - Reparations cables, 1945, 1946 (Box 98, Folder 1522)
    - Valuation, 1945, 1946 (Box 98, Folder 1523)
  - Miscellanea
    - The Federalist, 1963 (Box 99, Folder 1524)
    - The Veterans Administration and the Environmental Policies of the U.S. Government, 1971 (Box 99, Folder 1525-1526)